Sidney Robertson Cowell Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Correspondence, 1908-1988, bulk 1920-1979 (Box 1-5)
  - Family, 1908-1988 (Box 4-5)
    - Cotton, Anne Wendela Morrison (SRC's sister), 1965-1977, undated, SRC to AC. (Box-folder 4/8)
    - Cotton, Anne Wendela Morrison, 1960-1964, AC to SRC. (Box-folder 4/9)
    - Cotton, Anne Wendela Morrison, 1964-1965, AC to SRC. (Box-folder 4/10)
    - Cotton, Anne Wendela Morrison, 1966-1977, AC to SRC. (Box-folder 4/11)
    - Cowell, Henry, 1938, SRC to HC. (Box-folder 4/12)
    - Cowell, Olive (SRC's mother-in-law), 1941-1948, SRC to OC. (Box-folder 4/13)
    - Cowell, Olive, 1948-1976, SRC to OC. (Box-folder 4/14)
    - Cowell, Olive, 1976-1980, undated, SRC to OC. (Box-folder 4/15)
    - Cowell, Olive, 1976-1977, OC to SRC. (Box-folder 4/16)
    - Cowell, Olive, 1977-1981, OC to SRC. (Box-folder 4/17)
    - Hawkins, Charles Albert (SRC's father), 1921, undated, SRC to CAH. (Box-folder 4/18)
    - Hawkins, Charles Albert, 1921-1922, 1937-1952, CAH to SRC and other writings by CAH. (Box-folder 4/19)
    - Hawkins, Charles Ernest (SRC's half-brother), 1962, 1966 (Box-folder 4/20)
    - Hawkins, Helen, 1968, 1986-1988 (Box-folder 4/21)
    - Hawkins, John “Bud” (SRC's brother), 1912, 1964, undated (Box-folder 4/22)
    - Hawkins, Mabel “Muz” Morrison (SRC's mother), 1911-1919, SRC to MMH. (Box-folder 4/23)
    - Hawkins, Mabel “Muz” Morrison, 1920-1921 May, SRC to MMH. (Box-folder 4/24)
    - Hawkins, Mabel “Muz” Morrison, 1921 Oct.-1921 Dec., SRC to MMH. (Box-folder 5/1)
    - Hawkins, Mabel “Muz” Morrison, 1922-1925, SRC to MMH. (Box-folder 5/2)
    - Hawkins, Mabel “Muz” Morrison, 1934 Oct.-1935 Sept., SRC to MMH. (Box-folder 5/3)
    - Hawkins, Mabel “Muz” Morrison, 1935-1936 May, SRC to MMH. (Box-folder 5/4)
    - Hawkins, Mabel “Muz” Morrison, 1936 June-1937 May, SRC to MMH. (Box-folder 5/5)
    - Hawkins, Mabel “Muz” Morrison, 1930s, SRC to MMH. (Box-folder 5/6)
    - Hawkins, Mabel “Muz” Morrison, 1940s, SRC to MMH. (Box-folder 5/7)
    - Hawkins, Mabel “Muz” Morrison, undated, SRC to MMH. (Box-folder 5/8-9)
    - Hawkins, Mabel “Muz” Morrison, 1908, 1916, 1940-1943, MMH to her husband and to SRC. (Box-folder 5/10)
    - Hawkins, Mabel “Muz” Morrison, 1912, 1916, 1934-1935, 1943, To MMH from others. (Box-folder 5/11)
    - Hawkins, Odelia Comba (SRC's step-mother), 1941-1953 (Box-folder 5/12)
    - Insley, Ida E., 1955-1960, In addition to letters from Ida Insley to SRC, this material contains letters from others relating to Ida Insley’s death and her last will and testament. (Box-folder 5/13)
    - Mibach, H. J., 1956, 1962 (Box-folder 5/14)
    - Mibach, Jeane Mary Morrison (SRC's sister), 1957 (Box-folder 5/15)
    - Mibach, Lisa (SRC's niece), 1954-1963, 1987 (Box-folder 5/16)
    - Robertson, Kenneth (SRC's ex-husband), 1937, undated (Box-folder 5/17)
    - Betsy (niece), 1983 (Box-folder 5/18)
    - Nancy (niece), 1985 (Box-folder 5/19)
    - Sally (sister-in-law), 1968, 1981-1983, undated (Box-folder 5/20)
    - To family from SRC, 1912-1921 (Box-folder 5/21)
    - To family from SRC, 1922-[1928?] (Box-folder 5/22)
    - To family from SRC, 1941, undated (Box-folder 5/23)
- Materials Relating to Fieldwork, 1936-1962 (Box 6-9)
  Materials related to Cowell’s field recording trips, from various phases of her career, including reports, fieldnotes, correspondence, memoranda, training documents, lists of songs and recordings, song pamphlets, song transcriptions, articles, drafts of reports and handwritten notes.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Resettlement Administration Field Trip to North Carolina with John Lomax, 1936
    Final report, fieldnotes, annotated song list, correspondence.
    - “Report on Two Weeks’ Trip to North Carolina,” 1936, Written by Sidney Robertson with John Lomax and Frank Brown. (Box-folder 6/1)
    - Fieldnotes, 1936 (Box-folder 6/2)
    - “Titles and Notes on Tunes that Turned Up in One Form or Another at the Mountain Music and Dance Contests at Asheville, North Carolina, July 23-25, 1936” (Box-folder 6/3)
    - Correspondence, 1936 see also Container 2, Lomax, John see also Container 3, Seeger, Charles (Box-folder 6/4)
  - Resettlement Administration, 1936-1938
    Correspondence, memoranda, field reports, fieldnotes, training documents, song lists, song pamphlets, articles.
    Correspondence, memoranda, field reports and notes are arranged chronologically.
    - Correspondence, memoranda, notes, 1936 Jan.-Oct. (Box-folder 6/5)
    - Correspondence, memoranda, field reports, 1936 Nov. (Box-folder 6/6)
    - Correspondence, memoranda, fieldnotes, 1936 Nov. 21-23 (Box-folder 6/7)
    - Correspondence, memoranda, reports, 1936 Nov. 27-Dec. 30 (Box-folder 6/8)
    - Correspondence, memoranda, notes, reports, 1937 Jan.-Feb. (Box-folder 6/9)
    - Correspondence, memoranda, notes, 1937 Mar.-Apr. 4 (Box-folder 6/10)
    - Correspondence, fieldnotes, 1937 May-June (Box-folder 6/11)
    - Correspondence, memoranda, reports, 1937 July-Sept. (Box-folder 6/12)
    - Correspondence, reports, 1937 Oct.-Dec. (Box-folder 6/13)
    - Correspondence, memoranda, 1938 Jan., undated (Box-folder 6/14)
    - “Collection of American Traditional Music,” undated (Box-folder 6/15)
    - Drafts of music program memorandum, 1936 (Box-folder 6/16)
    - Training documents, undated (Box-folder 6/17)
    - “Harmonica Playing Bibliography,” undated, Music Memorandum, no. 12. Includes drafts. (Box-folder 6/18)
    - “Mrs. Dusenbury,” undated (Box-folder 6/19)
    - “Proposed List of Songs for Publication in Song Sheet Form,” 1936 Aug. 22 (Box-folder 6/20)
    - “Reservations and Limitations on Records, SR Series, nos. 1-156,” undated (Box-folder 6/21)
    - Lists of recordings from National Folk Festival and from Minn. and Wis., 1937 (Box-folder 6/22)
    - Lists of songs (Box-folder 6/23)
    - Information on playing recordings and other topics (Box-folder 6/24)
    - Song pamphlets, No. 8 is missing. (Box-folder 6/25)
    - “Accession List of Records” from the Special Skills Division, undated (Box-folder 6/26)
    - Articles on the Resettlement Administration (Box-folder 6/27)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 6/28)
  - California Folk Music Project, 1937-1954
    Final report, notes, lists of songs, correspondence.
    - “A Study of California Folk Music,” 1940 Jan. (Box-folder 7/1)
    - “Outline for a Book Tentatively Called Folksong in California,” 1954 July (Box-folder 7/2)
    - Handwritten notes for “Folksong in California” (Box-folder 7/3)
    - Checklist of recordings made for the California Folk Music Project, 1937 July-1939, July 18 (Box-folder 7/4)
    - Lists of California folk music, 1938-1939, 1954, undated, Includes performers and may include dates and places and annotations by Sidney Robertson Cowell. Includes list of Calif. recordings for the Sidney Robertson Cowell Duplication Project at the Library of Congress. (Box-folder 7/5)
    - Correspondence, 1938 (Box-folder 7/6)
    - Black, Eleanora and Sidney Robertson, comp. The Gold Rush Song Book. San Francisco: Colt Press, 1940. (Box-folder 7/7)
  - Carrie Grover from Gorham, Maine, 1941
    List of recordings.
    - “Records of the Singing and Fiddle Playing of Mrs. Carrie Grover, from Gorham, Maine” (Box-folder 7/8)
  - Appalachian Trip with Maud Karpeles, 1950
    Handwritten diary, notes, list of recordings.
    - Handwritten diary and notes (Box-folder 7/9)
    - Typewritten notes, 1950 Sept. 8- Oct. 18 (Box-folder 7/10)
    - “Tape Recordings Made in the Southern Appalachian Mountains, Sept.-Oct. 1950,” by Maud Karpeles and Sidney Robertson Cowell (Box-folder 7/11)
  - Wolf River Songs and Ford-Walker Family, 1952-1957
    Drafts of article, notes, song sheets, lists of songs.
    - Cowell, Sidney Robertson. Wolf River Songs. New York: Folkways Records, 1956. (Box-folder 7/12)
    - Typewritten drafts for Wolf River Songs, [1952-1954?] (Box-folder 7/13)
    - Handwritten notes for Wolf River Songs, [1952-1954?] (Box-folder 7/14)
    - Song sheets with accompanying notes and annotations (Box-folder 7/15)
    - “Sidney Robertson Cowell Duplication Project,” 1957 Dec. 10, From Library of Congress. List of songs with names of performer, date and place of recording. (Box-folder 7/16)
  - Songs from Cape Breton Island, 1950-1962
    Drafts of article, song sheets, song transcriptions, list of recordings, correspondence, article, program sheets.
    - Cowell, Sidney Robertson and John P. Hughes. Songs from Cape Breton Island. New York: Folkways Records, 1955. (Box-folder 7/17)
    - Drafts for sections of Songs from Cape Breton Island, undated (Box-folder 7/18)
    - Song sheets with notes and annotations, undated (Box-folder 7/19)
    - Transcriptions of songs recorded of North Shore Singers in Nova Scotia, Newton, Mass. and at Harvard, 1950-1953 or 1954 (Box-folder 8/1)
    - Lists of recordings from the project, including from a Library of Congress Sidney Robertson Cowell duplication project (Box-folder 8/2)
    - Correspondence, 1953-1955 (Box-folder 8/3)
    - Abstract of “The Connection between the Precenting of Psalms on Cape Breton Island and in Colonial New England Churches,” 1962 (Box-folder 8/4)
    - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 8/5)
    - Program sheets, 1953 (Box-folder 8/6)
    - Travel materials (Box-folder 8/7)
  - Songs of Aran, 1955-1957
    Song sheets and transcriptions with annotations.
    - Cowell, Sidney Robertson. Songs of Aran. New York: Folkways Records, 1957 (Box-folder 8/8)
    - Song sheets and transcriptions with notes and annotations, [1955-1956?]., Includes sheets of recordings from the Sidney Robertson Cowell Duplication Project at the Library of Congress. (Box-folder 8/9)
  - Travels in Asia and the Middle East, 1955-1957
    Final reports, drafts, anecdotes, notes.
    Arranged alphabetically by country.
    - “A Note on Music in Colombo (Ceylon),” undated (Box-folder 8/10)
    - “Report on Music in Hong Kong,” undated (Box-folder 8/11)
    - “A Note on Music in Macao (Macau),” undated (Box-folder 8/12)
    - “Report on Music in Madras and Bombay,” undated (Box-folder 8/13)
    - “A Report to the Rockefeller Foundation on Music in Iran,” undated (Box-folder 8/14)
    - “Persian Tales: SRC to S.E. Iran,” undated (Box-folder 8/15)
    - “Persian Tales: Iranian WPA,” undated (Box-folder 8/16)
    - “Persian Tales and Travelogue, cont’d.,” undated (Box-folder 8/17)
    - “From SRC’s Notebook: Recording Session at Nomad Encampment outside Abadan,” undated (Box-folder 9/1)
    - Random anecdotes, notes and comments about Iran, undated, Includes list of recordings from the Sidney Robertson Cowell Duplication Project at the Library of Congress. (Box-folder 9/2)
    - “A Note on Korean Performances (Orchestra, Ballet) Heard in Hong Kong,” March 1957 (Box-folder 9/3)
    - “A Report to the Rockefeller Foundation on Music in Lebanon,” undated (Box-folder 9/4)
    - “A Report to the Rockefeller Foundation on Music in Pakistan,” undated (Box-folder 9/5)
    - “A Report on Music in Singapore,” undated (Box-folder 9/6)
    - “Report on Music in Thailand,” undated (Box-folder 9/7)
    - “A Report to the Rockefeller Foundation on Music in Turkey,” undated (Box-folder 9/8)
- Materials Relating to Henry Cowell, 1915-1992 (Box 9-16, 29)
  Personal narratives by Sidney Robertson Cowell on Henry Cowell's life and work; articles and essays by and about Henry Cowell; discographical material; and photocopies of a selection of Henry Cowell holographs with annotations by Sidney Robertson Cowell.
  - Miscellaneous Material by and about Henry Cowell, 1920-1992
    Personal narratives by Sidney Robertson Cowell, discographical material, information about family, articles and essays by Henry Cowell, articles about Henry Cowell, clippings.
    - Narratives about Henry Cowell and Sidney Robertson Cowell written by SRC, 1971, undated (Box-folder 9/9)
    - Biographical essay on Henry Cowell (possibly written by SRC), undated (Box-folder 9/10)
    - Narrative on honors bestowed upon Henry Cowell, written by SRC, 1990 (Box-folder 9/11)
    - “HC and Foreign State Department Assignments,” written by SRC, 1990 (Box-folder 9/12)
    - Material on Henry Cowell and Iran, 1957, 1975-1977, 1988, undated (Box-folder 9/13)
    - “HC and the National Institute of Arts and Letters,” written by SRC, 1990 (Box-folder 9/14)
    - Narrative on Henry Cowell’s wristwatch, written by SRC, 1990 (Box-folder 9/15)
    - Materials relating to Henry Cowell’s discography, Includes SRC’s addenda to American Music Recordings: A Discography of 20th-Century U.S. Composers, 1992 (Box-folder 9/16)
    - “Anniversary Pieces: Music by Henry Cowell for His Wife, 1941-1965,” list compiled in 1979 (Box-folder 9/17)
    - “Music photocopied for me in 1985, from a closed private collection, which I may not identify, in Northern California,” 1985 see also Container 29 (Box-folder 9/18)
    - Materials relating to Olive Cowell (Henry Cowell’s stepmother), 1976, 1990 (Box-folder 9/19)
    - “Henrietta,” by Sidney Robertson Cowell, undated, A narrative about Henry Cowell’s first stepmother. (Box-folder 9/20)
    - Miscellaneous documents by SRC on Henry Cowell, undated (Box-folder 9/21)
    - “The Composer’s World,” by Henry Cowell, 1961 (Box-folder 9/22)
    - “International Music?” by Henry Cowell, 1961 (Box-folder 9/23)
    - “Oriental Influence on Western Music,” by Henry Cowell, 1961 (Box-folder 9/24)
    - “Piano Instruction Course,” by Henry Cowell, 1920 (Box-folder 9/25)
    - “Music is My Weapon” essay by Henry Cowell, [194?], Photocopy of essay from This I Believe (Series 2), ed. by Raymond Swing, 1954. (Box-folder 9/26)
    - “Tonal Therapy,” by Henry Cowell, 1922 (Box-folder 9/27)
    - “The Music of Henry Cowell,” by Hugo Weisgall, Reprint from The Musical Quarterly, October 1959. (Box-folder 9/28)
    - Henry Cowell: March 10, 1912, 50th Anniversary/March 11, 1897, 65th Birthday. S.l.: Broadcast Music, Inc., 1962 (Box-folder 9/29)
    - “Piano Music” by Henry Cowell. New York: Folkways Records, 1963, Handwritten comment by SRC: “mostly by SRC.” (Box-folder 9/30)
    - “How May a Composer Live in the Whole World of Music?” by David Hall, 1964 (Box-folder 9/31)
    - “Henry Cowell BMI.” S.l.: Broadcast Music, Inc., 1965 (Box-folder 10/1)
    - Newspaper clipping annotated by SRC, 1987 (Box-folder 10/2)
  - “Henry by Sidney” Material, circa 1980-circa 1990
    Draft material for a biography that Sidney Robertson Cowell was planning to write about Henry Cowell called “Henry by Sidney.”
    - Draft material for biography (Box-folder 10/3-26)
    - Draft material for biography (Box-folder 11/1-15)
    - Draft material for biography (Box-folder 12/1-23)
    - Draft material for biography (Box-folder 13/1-18)
    - Draft material for biography (Box-folder 14/1-16)
    - Draft material for biography (Box-folder 15/1-12)
    - Draft material for biography (Box-folder 16/1-9)
  - Music by Henry Cowell, 1915-circa 1950
    Photocopies of a selection of Henry Cowell holographs that are held in the Library of Congress Music Division. Many contain annotations by Sidney Robertson Cowell.
    Arranged alphabetically by title.
    - “The Changes Change” Continuation, 1917, Lichtenwanger no. 954. (Box-folder 29/1)
    - Chrysanthemums, 1936, Lichtenwanger no. 526. (Box-folder 29/10)
    - Clusteriana no. 1: Analysis of tone cluster examples in the form of movement of one cluster, 1916-1917?, Lichtenwanger no. 956. (Box-folder 29/11)
    - Consecration, 1917, Lichtenwanger no. 230. (Box-folder 29/2)
    - For Violin, [1924-1926?], Lichtenwanger no. 962. (Box-folder 29/3)
    - For Xmas ’20, 1920, Lichtenwanger no. 312. (Box-folder 29/4)
    - Japanese children’s song, A transcription of Chi Papa (The Bird) by Henry Cowell from SRC’s tape made circa 1950. (Box-folder 29/12)
    - Letter [to J.O. Varian], [1915-1916?], Lichtenwanger no. 217. (Box-folder 29/5)
    - Polyphonica no. 1, 1916, Lichtenwanger no. 953. (Box-folder 29/6)
    - Polyphonica no. 2, 1916, Lichtenwanger no. 953. (Box-folder 29/7)
    - System, 1918-1919, Lichtenwanger no. 258. (Box-folder 29/8)
    - The Word Eternal, 1917?, Lichtenwanger no. 955 (Box-folder 29/9)
- Biographical Material, 1901-1985, bulk 1929-1985 (Box 17)
  Autobiographical narratives and essays; anecdotes, personal thoughts and musings on various subjects; articles, clippings and reviews; family histories and documents; drawings; diary; passport; diploma from Stanford University.
  - Autobiographical narratives (drafts), 1970, undated (Box-folder 17/1)
  - Autobiographical narratives (drafts), 1971, undated (Box-folder 17/2)
  - Biographical essays and curriculum vita, 1978, undated (Box-folder 17/3)
  - Anecdotes from travels in the 1930s, circa 1947 (Box-folder 17/4)
  - Diary--Ireland, London, Amsterdam, Lugano, Greece, 1956 (Box-folder 17/5)
  - Personal health history, 1984 (Box-folder 17/6)
  - Anecdotes from various dates (Box-folder 17/7)
  - Personal thoughts (Box-folder 17/8)
  - “What It Is to Grow Old,” handwritten by SRC, undated (Box-folder 17/9)
  - Notices of activities, 1951, 1959, undated (Box-folder 17/10)
  - Miscellaneous notes, musings (Box-folder 17/11)
  - Articles about Sidney Robertson Cowell, 1957, 1980, 1982 (Box-folder 17/12)
  - Clippings about Sidney Robertson Cowell and reviews of her work, 1929-1985, undated (Box-folder 17/13)
  - Identity documents, 1921, 1969 (Box-folder 17/14)
  - Leland Stanford Junior University diploma of graduation, 1924 (Box-folder 17/15)
  - Miscellaneous biographical material (Box-folder 17/16)
  - Drawings by Sidney Robertson Cowell (Box-folder 17/17)
  - Miscellaneous (Box-folder 17/18)
  - Hawkins and Morrison-Tonnelle family histories, undated (Box-folder 17/19)
  - Miscellaneous Hawkins family documents (Box-folder 17/20)
  - Documents relating to Odelia Comba Hawkins relatives, 1901 (Box-folder 17/21)
  - Letter to John regarding the Binkley family relations, 1982 (Box-folder 17/22)
- Writings and Publications, 1911-1990 (Box 18-20)
  Published articles, essays, program notes, and reviews by Sidney Robertson Cowell; unpublished writings by Sidney Robertson Cowell, including drafts, anecdotes, personal narratives, project proposals, class notes, fiction and poetry; also includes books, journals, and reports written by others.
  - Published Writings by Sidney Robertson Cowell, 1938-1988
    Articles, essays, program notes, reviews, and obituaries.
    - “The Songs of a Nation Collect a Forgotten Claim,” 1938 (Box-folder 18/1)
    - “The Recording of Folk Music in California,” 1942 (Box-folder 18/2)
    - American Folk Song and Folk Lore: A Regional Bibliography, 1942 (Box-folder 18/3)
    - “White Spirituals,” 1943 (Box-folder 18/4)
    - Program notes written for Boston Symphony Orchestra performance of Henry Cowell’s Short symphony no. 4, 1947 (Box-folder 18/5)
    - “Old Harp Singing,” 1951 (Box-folder 18/6)
    - Review of Dances of Early California Days, by Lucile K. Czarnowski, [1950?] (Box-folder 18/7)
    - Review of American Folk Songs of Protest, by John Greenway, [1953?] (Box-folder 18/8)
    - “Songs from Cape Breton Island,” 1955 (Box-folder 18/9)
    - “Wolf River Songs,” 1956 (Box-folder 18/10)
    - “Songs of Aran,” 1957 (Box-folder 18/11)
    - Review of The Traditional Tunes of the Child Ballads, vol. I, by Bertrand Harris Bronson, [1959?] (Box-folder 18/12)
    - Review of Shanties from the Seven Seas, compiled by Stan Hugill, 1961 (Box-folder 18/13)
    - “The Connection between the Precenting of Psalms on Cape Breton Island and in Colonial New England Churches,” 1962 (Box-folder 18/14)
    - Obituary of Percy Grainger, 1962 (Box-folder 18/15)
    - Review of The Traditional Tunes of the Child Ballads, vol. II, by Bertrand Harris Bronson, 1963 (Box-folder 18/16)
    - “Early American Spirituals,” 1967 (Box-folder 18/17)
    - Obituary of Charles Seeger, 1979 (Box-folder 18/18)
    - Introduction in Jaime de Angulo: The Music of the Indians of Northern California, 1988 (Box-folder 18/19)
    - Two reviews attributed to Henry Cowell but were actually written by SRC, 1945, 1959 (Box-folder 18/20)
    - Miscellaneous items, 1956, 1987, undated (Box-folder 18/21)
  - Unpublished Writings by Sidney Robertson Cowell, 1911-1990
    - Narratives on Collecting, 1986-1990
      Narratives, drafts of talks, notes, anecdotes, letters.
      - Narrative on California field collecting, undated (Box-folder 19/1)
      - “Cinderella Kinnaird,” undated (Box-folder 19/2)
      - Narrative on Mrs. Dusenberry, undated (Box-folder 19/3)
      - Narrative on California field collecting, 1990 (Box-folder 19/4)
      - Narrative on field recordings, undated (Box-folder 19/5)
      - “Fieldwork in Three Great Lake States,” undated (Box-folder 19/6)
      - “First Solo Field Recordings, Nov. 10, 1936,” undated (Box-folder 19/7)
      - Narrative on Leon Henderson, 1986 (Box-folder 19/8)
      - “Lady on Wheels,” undated (Box-folder 19/9)
      - “Missing Uncle Charlie,” 1990 (Box-folder 19/10)
      - “My collection of folk music is unusual in these respects ...” undated (Box-folder 19/11)
      - “Random notes on SRC’s folksong collecting in late 1930s,” undated (Box-folder 19/12)
      - “The Walker-Ford Family of Singers,” 1990 (Box-folder 19/13)
      - Wayfaring Stranger—song sheet #9, undated (Box-folder 19/14)
      - 1936 remembrance, 1990 (Box-folder 19/15)
      - Resettlement Administration story, 1990 (Box-folder 19/16)
      - Collecting anecdote, 1990 (Box-folder 19/17)
      - Edson’s tune book, undated (Box-folder 19/18)
      - Narrative about traveling in Japan, undated (Box-folder 19/19)
      - Letters on folk singing, to Sam Eskin, undated (Box-folder 19/20)
      - Handwritten narrative on folk song collecting, undated (Box-folder 19/21)
    - Drafts of Reviews, Papers, and Reports, 1949-circa 1967
      - Draft of review for American Folk Songs of Protest, [1953?] (Box-folder 19/22)
      - Draft of “The Connection between the Melismatic Psalm Singing of Cape Breton and of Colonial New England Churches,” 1961 (Box-folder 19/23)
      - Draft of “Early American Carols,” [1967?] (Box-folder 19/24)
      - Draft of “Early American Spirituals,” 1966, Includes letter from the editor, song sheets and other notes. (Box-folder 19/25)
      - Draft of review for England’s Dances by Douglas Kennedy, [1949?] (Box-folder 19/26)
      - Draft of review for The English and Scottish Popular Ballads and Great British Ballads Not Found in Child, undated (Box-folder 19/27)
      - Draft of paper on improvisation, rhythm in education and children’s music, undated (Box-folder 19/28)
      - Draft of “Lessons with the Boston Symphony,” 1954, This was ghost-written for Henry Cowell. (Box-folder 19/29)
      - Drafts for “Music in Ghana,” [196-] (Box-folder 19/30)
      - Draft of review for Negro Folk Music of Alabama, undated (Box-folder 19/31)
      - Draft of review for Vance Randolph’s publications on the Ozarks, undated (Box-folder 19/32)
      - Draft of an obituary for Ruth Crawford Seeger, 1954 (Box-folder 19/33)
      - Draft of review for Shanties from the Seven Seas, [1961?] (Box-folder 19/34)
      - Draft of review for Songs of the Irish, [1960?] (Box-folder 19/35)
      - Drafts of “Three Generations of Folk Singers in the United States,” [195-?] (Box-folder 19/36)
      - Draft of review for The Traditional Tunes of the Child Ballads, vol. I, [1959?] (Box-folder 19/37)
      - Draft of review for The Traditional Tunes of the Child Ballads, vol. II, [1963?] (Box-folder 19/38)
      - Draft of a review for Wayfaring Stranger, undated (Box-folder 19/39)
      - Draft and notes for “White Spirituals,” undated (Box-folder 19/40)
    - Miscellaneous, 1911-1967
      Project proposals, class notes, fiction and poetry.